Guide to the Montana Power Company Predecessor Company records 1880-1947
Montana Historical Society
- Great Falls Water Power and Townsite Company / Great Falls Townsite Company
  - Financial Records
    - Rent ledger index, 1906-1919 (Box-folder 60 / 10)
    - Report to Federal Trade Commission, 1928 (Box-folder 61 / 1)
    - Sale of power from Rainbow and Black Eagle dams, 1892-1910 (Box-folder 61 / 2)
    - Taxes: Cascade County and other counties, 1915-1940 (Box-folder 61 / 3-8)
    - Lot contract accounts (includes Rainbow Hotel rentals) [Oversize Box], 1943-1944 (Oversizebox 7)
    - Taxes: United States stock tax (for Montana stock tax see subject file #14-1/2), 1912 (Box-folder 61 / 9)
    - Trial balances: Great Falls Townsite Company [Oversize Box], 1911-1936 (Oversizebox 7)
    - Trial balances: Great Falls Water Power and Townsite Company [Oversize Box], 1891-1896, 1903-1918 (Oversizebox 7)
    - Voucher register, 1908-1911 (Volume 133)
    - Voucher register and account distribution, 1941-1944 (Box-folder 61 / 10)
    - Wages for farm work, 1880s (Box-folder 61 / 11)
    - Miscellaneous (includes lot sale suspense account, estimates, property valuations, etc.), 1908-1928 (Box-folder 61 / 12)
  - Legal Documents
    - Abstracts of title, 1887-1889, 1919, 1941 (Box-folder 61 / 13-14)
    - Abstracts of title #1-10, 1908-1909 (Box-folder 61 / 15)
    - Abstracts of title #11-50, 1908-1909 (Box-folder 62 / 1-4)
    - Agreement with W.H. Bertsche et al., 1937 (Box-folder 63 / 1)
    - Agreement with Boston and Montana Consolidated Copper and Silver Mining Company, 1908 (Box-folder 63 / 2)
    - Bills of sale: houses on Upper Campbell Ranch, 1933 (Box-folder 63 / 3)
    - Building contract: Tribune Company, 1890 (Box-folder 63 / 4)
    - Certificates of redemption, 1912 (Box-folder 63 / 5)
    - Contracts, 1889-1908 (Box-folder 63 / 6)
    - Contracts: John D. Ryan sale of stock, 1909, 1913 (Box-folder 63 / 7)
    - Contracts with Montana Smelting Company, 1888-1890 (Box-folder 63 / 8)
    - Deed from James J. Hill, 1887 (Box-folder 63 / 9)
    - Deed to Cascade County for county poor farm, 1909 (Box-folder 63 / 10)
    - Deed to Great Falls Power Company, 1910 (Box-folder 63 / 11)
    - Deed to Great Falls Townsite Company, 1910 (Box-folder 63 / 12)
    - Deeds issued books: #1-6520 (including index) [also MF 456], 1891-1946 (Volume 134- 135)
    - Deeds to Great Falls Water Power and Townsite Company from miscellaneous people (list enclosed; see also: subject file #3 for deeds to Great Falls Townsite Company), 1887-1910 (Box-folder 63 / 13-14)
    - Deeds to lots [scattered], 1887-1946 (Box-folder 63 / 15-16)
    - Ferguson petition for survey of an island in Missouri River and protest thereto, 1901-1902 (Box-folder 63 / 17)
    - Leases: G-S, 1889-1907 (Box-folder 64 / 1)
    - Leases: A-Y (see also: subject file #19), 1910-1935 (Box-folder 64 / 2-3)
    - Legal opinions (re right to build dam against wishes of adjacent property owner; cancellation of old contracts; final deeds for contract consignees; riparian rights; etc.), 1895-1908 (Box-folder 64 / 4)
    - Lists of deeds and agreements: Samuel H. Nichols, 1887 (Box-folder 64 / 5)
    - Lists of delinquent lot contracts and contracts in effect, 1912 (Box-folder 64 / 6)
    - Lot books: Block #1-620 [also MF 456], 1887-1900 (Volume 136- 137)
    - Lot books: contracts #396-5639 (indexed) [also MF 456], 1888-1943 (Volume 138- 141)
    - Lot record: city additions [also MF 456], 1890-1942 (Volume 142)
    - Lot record: rural townships [also MF 456], 1882-1890 (Volume 143)
    - Permit to lay water pipe, 1891 (Box-folder 64 / 7)
    - Powers of attorney: Charles S. Hewitt; Paris Gibson, 1883-1884 (Box-folder 64 / 8)
    - Real estate record [partially duplicates lot books], 1890s (Volume 144)
    - Right of way for tranmission lines, 1909-1911 (Box-folder 64 / 9)
    - Royal Milling Company documents re flour mill site, 1892-1904 (Box-folder 64 / 10)
    - Silver Smelter deeds etc: Montana Smelting Company, 1888-1890 (Box-folder 64 / 11)
    - Silver Smelter deeds etc: Montana Smelting Company [Oversize: see Archives Map Case], 1888-1890 (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Warranty deeds [scattered], 1885-1913 (Box-folder 64 / 12)
    - Water record, 1892-1893 (Volume 145)
    - Frank Webster documents, 1892-1893 (Box-folder 64 / 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1888-1988, 1917-1936 (Box-folder 64 / 14-15)
  - Maps
    - Plats of Great Falls and various additions, 1910, 1928- 1930, undated (Box-folder 64 / 16)
    - Plats of Great [map showing holdings, 1910, of Company; Oversize: see Archives Map Case], 1910, 1928- 1930, undated (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Right of way, 1940 (Box-folder 64 / 17)
    - Right of way [Oversize: See Archives Map Case], 1940 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Organizational Records
    - Articles of incorporation and bylaws, 1887 (Box-folder 65 / 1)
    - Lists of officers, directors, and stockholders, 1887-1940 (Box-folder 65 / 2-3)
    - Minutes: Great Falls Water Power and Townsite Company (excerpts only), 1887-1934 (Box-folder 65 / 4)
    - Record book: Great Falls Townsite Company (includes articles of incorporation, bylaws, minutes, etc.), 1910-1941 (Box-folder 65 / 5)
    - Record book: Great Falls Townsite Company (items removed from book for preservation reasons), 1941-1944 (Box-folder 65 / 6)
    - Stockholder journal, 1887-1908 (Box-folder 65 / 7)
    - Stockholder ledgers, 1887-1915 (Volume 146- 148)
    - Stockholder ledger index, undated (Box-folder 65 / 8)
    - Stock valuation, 1943 (Box-folder 65 / 9)
    - Voting trust agreement, 1911-1913 (Box-folder 65 / 10)
    - Miscellaneous (includes extension of life of corporation; proxies; etc.), 1887-1931 (Box-folder 65 / 11)
  - Reports
    - "Survey of evidence desired in connection with the Great Falls properties", by L.V. Ketter, 1924 (Box-folder 65 / 12)
  - Subject Files
    - #1 Certificates of tax sales, 1896-1902 (Box-folder 66 / 1)
    - #2 Proposed road Montana Brewery to Boston and Montana Consolidated Copper and Silver Mining Company, 1894-1908 (Box-folder 66 / 2)
    - #2 Proposed road Montana Brewery to Boston and Montana Consolidated Copper and Silver Mining Company [Oversize: see Archives Map Case], 1894-1908 (Oversize-folder 1)
    - #3 Deeds to Great Falls Townsite Company, including tax deeds (see also: legal documents series for deeds to Great Falls Water Power and Townsite Company), 1912-1943 (Box-folder 66 / 3)
    - #3 Deeds from Great Falls Townsite Company (see also: legal documents series for deeds to lots from Great Falls Townsite Company), 1913-1941 (Box-folder 66 / 4)
    - #4 Valeria Way, Riverside Park, Black Eagle Park, Rainbow Park, 1909-1913 (Box-folder 66 / 5)
    - #4 Valeria Way, Riverside Park, Black Eagle Park, Rainbow Park [Oversize: see Archives Map Case], 1909-1913 (Oversize-folder 1)
    - #6 Great Northern Railway Company (also includes other railroads), 1890-1923 (Box-folder 66 / 6)
    - #7 Great Northern Railway Company, circa 1920 - 1939 (Box-folder 66 / 7)
    - #7 Great Northern Railway Company [Oversize: see Archives Map Case], circa 1920 - 1939 (Oversize-folder 1)
    - #10 Miscellaneous (list enclosed), 1889-1935 (Box-folder 66 / 8)
    - #10-1/2 Deeds to City of Great Falls, 1909-1931 (Box-folder 66 / 9)
    - #10-1/2 Deeds to City of Great Falls [Oversize: see Archives Map Case], 1909-1931 (Oversize-folder 1)
    - #11 Great Falls and Canada Railway Company, 1897-1899 (Box-folder 66 / 10)
    - #11-B Great Falls City Council resolutions (re streets, alleys, etc.), 1942 (Box-folder 66 / 11)
    - #11-C Park south of 10th Avenue South, 1942 (Box-folder 67 / 1)
    - #13 Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul Railway Company, 1912-1938 (Box-folder 67 / 2)
    - #14 Miscellaneous (includes list), 1909-1931 (Box-folder 67 / 3)
    - #14-1/2 Montana capital stock tax and corporate license tax, 1916-1932 (Box-folder 67 / 4)
    - #16 Inventories of lots (see also Financial Records), 1910 (Box-folder 67 / 5)
    - #17 Brewery sites [oversize maps in map case], 1890-1913 (Box-folder 67 / 6)
    - #19 Leases: B-Y (see also Legal Documents), 1923-1943 (Box-folder 67 / 7)
    - #20 YMCA, 1914 (Box-folder 67 / 8)
    - #21 Glass plant, 1914 (Box-folder 67 / 9)
    - #22 Brick plant [oversize maps in map case], 1915-1936 (Box-folder 67 / 10)
    - #23 Ford and Crutcher property, 5th Addition [oversize map in map case], 1904-1911 (Box-folder 67 / 11)
    - #24 List of records sent to Butte in 1918 (for records sent in 1941-1942 see Miscellany series); Power City Oil and Natural Gas Company, 1914-1918 (Box-folder 67 / 12)
    - #25 Montana Flour Mills Company; Stock Pavilion Company; Barkemeyer Grain and Seed Company, 1916-1943 (Box-folder 67 / 13)
    - #26 Montana Cord Tire Company; Joe Magagnini Macaroni Factory, 1916-1920 (Box-folder 67 / 14)
    - #28 Grain settlements on farming operations; Jensen and Siebel; G.W. Hallett; Montgomery Machinery Company, 1918-1939 (Box-folder 67 / 15)
    - #29 Miscellaneous (primarily re right of way, wheat allotments), 1930-1939 (Box-folder 68 / 1-2)
    - #29 Miscellaneous (primarily re right of way, wheat allotments) [Oversize: see Archives Map Case], 1930-1939 (Oversize-folder 2)
    - #30 American Refining Company, 1922 (Box-folder 68 / 3)
    - #30 American Refining Company [Oversize: see Archives Map Case], 1922 (Oversize-folder 3)
    - #31 Sunburst Refining Company, 1923-1926 (Box-folder 68 / 4)
    - #32 Annual reports of corporation, 1922-1936 (Box-folder 68 / 5)
    - #34 Montana Power Company easements, 1927-1943 (Box-folder 68 / 6)
    - #35 Gas line right of way: Montana Cities Gas Company, Great Falls Gas Company, 1927-1931 (Box-folder 68 / 7)
    - #36-38 Surveys, 1927-1931 (Box-folder 68 / 8-10)
    - #36-38 Surveys [Oversize: see Archives Map Case], 1927-1931 (Oversize-folder 3)
    - #40 Social Security, 1935 (Box-folder 68 / 11)
    - #41 Maps [list enclosed], circa 1930-1939 (Box-folder 68 / 12)
    - #41 Maps [Oversize: see Archives Map Case], circa 1930-1939 (Oversize-folder 4)
    - #42 Abstracts of title: Latter Day Saints Church, 1929-1930 (Box-folder 68 / 13)
    - #44 Second Addition, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 68 / 14)
    - #44 Second Addition [Oversize: see Archives Map Case], 1940-1941 (Oversize-folder 4)
    - #45 Community Hall Addition map, 1937 (Box-folder 68 / 15)
    - #45 Community Hall Addition map [Oversize: see Archives Map Case], 1940-1941 (Oversize-folder 4)
    - #46 Sunset Addition map, 1937 (Box-folder 68 / 16)
    - #46 Sunset Addition map [Oversize: see Archives Map Case], 1940-1941 (Oversize-folder 4)
    - #47 Fair Addition, 1941 (Box-folder 68 / 17)
    - #47 Fair Addition [Oversize: see Archives Map Case], 1940-1941 (Oversize-folder 4)
    - #125 "Papers relative to Iron Cross and Iron Crown mining claims, Running Wolf District, Meagher County, Montana", 1893-1944 (Box-folder 68 / 18)
    - Grading of Colorado Avenue in "Little Chicago", 1909 (Box-folder 68 / 19)
    - Grading of Colorado Avenue in "Little Chicago" [Oversize: see Archives Map Case], 1940-1941 (Oversize-folder 4)
    - "Guarantee by Ryan and Butte Electric and Power Company of obligations", 1908-1909 (Box-folder 68 / 20)
    - Mesa Power Company acquisition, 1934 (Box-folder 68 / 21)
    - "Sioux half-breed scrip" (includes correspondence with Collins Land Company), 1899-1902 (Box-folder 68 / 22)
    - Special Improvement Districts, 1906-1908 (Box-folder 68 / 23)
    - Squatters, 1909 (Box-folder 69 / 1)
    - Squatters [Oversize: see Archives Map Case], 1940-1941 (Oversize-folder 4)
    - Squatters: John Kowell, 1905-1906 (Box-folder 69 / 2)
    - Wagon bridge construction, 1887-1891 (Box-folder 69 / 3)
    - Wagon bridge construction: payroll, timebooks, pay checkstubs, assignments of wages, 1887-1888 (Box-folder 69 / 4)
  - Miscellany
    - List of corporate records sent to Butte (see also: Subject File #24), 1941-1942 (Box-folder 69 / 5)
- Harlowton Light and Water Company
  - Historical Material
    - Historical information file, 1912 (Box-folder 70 / 1)
- Havre Electric Company
  - Historical Material
    - Historical information file, undated (Box-folder 70 / 2)
  - Financial Records
    - Cash book, 1911-1914 (Volume 149)
    - General ledgers, 1904-1906 (Box-folder 70 / 3-4)
    - General ledgers, 1906-1914 (Volume 150- 152)
    - General ledgers, 1914-1918 (Box-folder 71 / 1-4)
    - General ledgers, 1919-1922 (Box-folder 72 / 1-4)
    - General ledgers, 1923-1926 (Box-folder 73 / 1-4)
    - General ledger, 1927 (Box-folder 74 / 1)
    - Journal, 1904-1915 (Box-folder 74 / 2)
    - Journal, 1912-1913 (Volume 153)
    - Operating statement and balance sheet, 1904 (Box-folder 74 / 3)
    - Trial balances [Oversize Box], 1908-1914 (Oversizebox 7)
    - Voucher registers, 1905-1916 (Volume 154- 156)
  - Legal Documents
    - Miscellaneous (includes agreements with Broadwater-Pepin Company; sale of company to Montana Power Company), 1904, 1914 (Box-folder 74 / 4)
  - Organizational Records
    - Record book (includes articles of incorporation, bylaws, minutes, and annual reports), 1904-1914 (Box-folder 74 / 5-6)
    - Stock certificates (blank), undated (Box-folder 74 / 7)
    - Stockholder journal, 1904-1907 (Box-folder 75 / 1)
    - Stockholder ledger, 1904-1907 (Box-folder 75 / 2)
- Havre Electric, Steam Heat and Telephone Company
  - Financial Records
    - Trial balance, January 1914 (Box-folder 75 / 3)
  - Organizational Records
    - Bylaws, 1910 (Box-folder 75 / 4)
    - Minutes, 1910-1911, 1914 (Box-folder 75 / 5-6)
    - Stock certificates (blank), 1910 (Box-folder 75 / 7)
    - Stockholder ledger and journal (common stock), 1910 (Box-folder 75 / 8)
    - Stockholder ledger and journal (preferred stock), 1910 (Box-folder 75 / 9)
    - Miscellaneous, 1910-1911 (Box-folder 75 / 10)
- Helena Electric Company
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Letterpress books, 1889-1894 (Box-folder 76 / 1-2)
  - Employment Records
    - Payrolls, 1891-1892 (Box-folder 76 / 3)
  - Financial Records
    - Cash book, 1890 (Box-folder 76 / 4)
    - Check register [labelled "Bank book"], 1890-1895 (Volume 157)
    - Customers' electric light book, 1890 (Volume 158)
    - General ledgers, 1890-1891 (Box-folder 77 / 1-2)
    - General ledger, 1891-1895 (Volume 159)
    - Insurance policy expirations, 1891-1893 (Box-folder 77 / 3)
    - Invoice book for electrical service (also includes some correspondence), 1891-1892 (Box-folder 77 / 4)
    - Invoice book for electrical service, 1892-1894 (Box-folder 78 / 1)
    - Journals (also used for various other purposes), 1890-1893 (Box-folder 78 / 2-3)
    - Journal, 1891-1895 (Volume 160)
    - Meter readings ledger, 1899-1900 (Box-folder 78 / 4)
    - Order book for service (also includes coal shipments), 1889-1894 (Box-folder 79 / 1)
    - Service book, 1890, 1892 (Box-folder 79 / 2)
    - Trial balances, 1891-1894 (Box-folder 79 / 3)
    - Voucher register, 1894 (Box-folder 79 / 4)
  - Organizational Records
    - Stock certificates (blank), undated (Box-folder 79 / 5)
    - Stockholder journal, 1890-1895 (Box-folder 79 / 6)
    - Stockholder ledger, 1890-1894 (Box-folder 79 / 7)
- Helena Electric Railway Company
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Letterpress books, 1890-1894 (Box-folder 80 / 1-2)
  - Financial Records
    - Daybook, 1891-1894 (Box-folder 80 / 3)
    - General ledgers, 1890-1894 (Volume 161- 162)
    - Insurance policy expirations, 1891-1895 (Box-folder 80 / 4)
    - Journals, 1890-1895 (Volume 163- 164)
    - Statements of passengers carried, etc., 1892-1894 (Box-folder 80 / 5)
    - Trial balances [new company, organized 1927], 1927-1929 (Volume 165)
    - Voucher registers, 1890-1894 (Volume 166- 167)
  - Organizational Records
    - Minute book (includes bylaws), 1891-1894 (Box-folder 81 / 1)
    - Minute book: Executive Committee, 1891-1894 (Box-folder 81 / 2)
    - Stock certificates (blank), undated (Box-folder 81 / 3)
    - Stockholder journal, 1891-1894 (Box-folder 81 / 4)
    - Stockholder ledger, 1891-1894 (Box-folder 81 / 5)
- Helena Gas and Electric Company
  - Historical Material
    - Chronology of Helena companies, 1884-1928 (Box-folder 81 / 6)
  - Financial Records
    - Checkstubs, 1929 (Box-folder 81 / 7)
    - General ledger, 1927-1928 (Volume 168)
    - General ledger, 1927-1929 (Box-folder 81 / 8)
    - Journals (lists "sets" and "stock"), 1928-1929 (Box-folder 81 / 9-10)
    - Trial balances, 1927-1928 (Volume 169)
    - Voucher register [Oversize Box], 1927-1928 (Oversizebox 8)
    - Unidentified meter sheets (include meter number, and appliances installed), 1929 (Box-folder 81 / 11)
  - Subject File
    - Acquisition of company by Montana Power Company, 1928-1942 (Box-folder 81 / 12)
  - Clippings
    - New office, 1929 (Box-folder 81 / 13)
- Helena Gas Light and Coke Company
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Letterpress book [water damaged, many letters illegible], 1891-1894 (Box-folder 82 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - Account with Montana National Bank, 1888-1890 (Box-folder 82 / 2)
    - Check register [labelled "Bank book"], 1890-1894 (Volume 170)
    - Daily record of gas produced, coal consumed, etc., 1885-1891 (Box-folder 82 / 3)
    - Daybooks, 1885-1893 (Box-folder 82 / 4-5)
    - Daybook, 1894 (Box-folder 83 / 1)
    - Gas, coke, and tar collections, 1889-1890 (Box-folder 83 / 2)
    - General ledger, 1893-1894 (Volume 171)
    - Journal, 1888-1891 (Box-folder 83 / 3)
    - Journal, 1891-1895 (Volume 172)
    - Journal: Stonehouse account and private service account, 1892-1897 (Box-folder 83 / 4)
    - Receiving book (record of gas use), 1885-1888 (Box-folder 83 / 5)
    - Receiving book (record of gas use), 1889-1890 (Volume 173)
    - Trial balances, 1885-1895 (Box-folder 84 / 1-2)
  - Organizational Records
    - Minutes, 1892-1894 (Box-folder 84 / 3)
    - Stock certificates, 1884-1895 (Box-folder 84 / 4)
    - Stockholder journal, 1884-1885 (Box-folder 84 / 5)
    - Stockholder ledger, 1884-1894 (Box-folder 84 / 6)
    - Stockholder ledger index, 1884-1886 (Box-folder 84 / 7)
  - Miscellany
    - Applications for gas service, 1884-1891 (Box-folder 84 / 8)
- Helena Hot Springs and Smelter Railroad Company
  - Employment Records
    - Time book (re construction), 1889-1890 (Box-folder 85 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - Daybook, 1890 (Box-folder 85 / 2)
- Helena Light and Railway Company
  - Court Papers
    - Irving Bank-Columbia Trust Company vs. Helena Light and Railway Company foreclosure, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 85 / 3)
    - F.J. Edwards and Fred Naegele vs. Helena Light and Railway Company, 1913 (Box-folder 85 / 4)
  - Financial Records
    - Details of construction expense: gas, electric and railway, 1905-1929 (Volume 174)
    - Distribution of accounts, 1919-1927 (Volume 175)
    - Financial statements [water-damaged, many entries illegible], 1916-1921 (Box-folder 86 / 1-2)
    - General ledgers, 1905-1927 (Volume 176- 182)
    - Journal, 1905-1907 (Volume 183)
    - Journal [Oversize Box], 1909-1920 (Oversizebox 8)
    - Trial balances, 1905-1927 (Volume 184- 185)
    - Trial balance: receivership, September 1927 (Box-folder 86 / 3)
    - "Valuation of the gas property of the Helena Light and Railway Company, Helena, Montana", 1918 (Box-folder 86 / 4)
    - Voucher registers, 1905-1921 (Volume 186- 187)
  - Legal Documents
    - Mortgage; union contract, 1905, 1910 (Box-folder 86 / 5)
  - Organizational Records
    - Stockholder ledger: common stock, 1906 (Box-folder 86 / 6)
    - Stockholder ledger: preferred stock, 1906 (Box-folder 86 / 7)
    - Stockholder list, 1909 (Box-folder 86 / 8)
  - Reports
    - Report by Public Service Commissioner J.H. Bonner, 1919 (Box-folder 86 / 9)
  - Miscellany
    - Electric meter testing record [Oversize Box], 1911-1920 (Oversizebox 8)
    - Electric meter testing record, 1923-1928 (Box-folder 86 / 10)
    - List of gas customers, 1920 (Box-folder 86 / 11)
- Helena Light and Traction Company
  - Financial Records
    - General ledger, 1902-1905 (Volume 188)
    - Journal, 1902-1905 (Volume 189)
  - Organizational Records
    - Stockholder ledger, 1902-1905 (Box-folder 87 / 1)
- Helena Motor Railway Company
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Letterpress book, 1888-1889 (Box-folder 87 / 2)
  - Employment Records
    - Payrolls: J.J. Palmer, contractor, 1888-1889 (Volume 190)
  - Financial Records
    - Trial balances, 1889 (Volume 191)
    - Voucher registers, 1888-1889 (Volume 192- 194)
  - Organizational Records
    - Stock certificates (blank), undated (Box-folder 87 / 3)
- Helena Power and Light Company
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Letterpress book, 1894-1897 (Box-folder 87 / 4)
    - Letterpress books, 1897-1900 (Box-folder 88 / 1-3)
    - Letterpress book, 1900-1901 (Box-folder 89 / 1)
  - Employment Records
    - Payrolls, 1889-1890, 1895, 1897 (Box-folder 89 / 2-4)
  - Financial Records
    - Electric customers invoices (back of volume contains requests for payment of delinquent accounts), 1894-1895 (Box-folder 89 / 5)
    - Electric Department coal record, 1895-1898 (Box-folder 89 / 6-7)
    - Electric Department "Superintendent's record of miscellaneous accounts", 1894-1897 (Box-folder 90 / 1)
    - Expense record (includes payroll), 1891-1892 (Box-folder 90 / 2)
    - Gas Department "Superintendent's record of miscellaneous accounts", 1894-1897 (Box-folder 90 / 3)
    - Gas Works record, 1892-1897 (Box-folder 90 / 4)
    - General ledgers, 1889-1890 (Box-folder 90 / 5-6)
    - General ledger, 1894-1902 (Volume 195)
    - Journal, 1889-1890 (Box-folder 91 / 1)
    - Journal, 1894-1902 (Volume 196)
    - Monthly charges for lights [Oversize Box], 188? (Oversizebox 8)
    - Purchase journal [?], 1889-1890 (Box-folder 91 / 2)
    - Receiver's cash book, 1902 (Oversizebox 8 [Oversize Box])
    - Receiver's journal, 1902 (Box-folder 91 / 3)
    - Secretary's financial reports, 1894-1898 (Volume 197)
    - Street railway inventories, 1894-1899 (Box-folder 91 / 4)
    - Street railway ticket record, 1894-1900 (Box-folder 91 / 5)
    - Superintendent's registers, 1894-1900 (Volume 198- 199)
    - Voucher register, 1894-1900 (Volume 200)
    - Miscellaneous, 1897-1898 (Box-folder 91 / 6)
  - Organizational Records
    - Stock certificates, 1889 (Box-folder 91 / 7)
  - Miscellany
    - Job book, 1897 (Box-folder 91 / 8)
    - Lamp renewal book, 1895-1897 (Box-folder 91 / 9)
    - Meter books (includes types of meters, customer, address, not indexed), 1905-1907 (Box-folder 92 / 1)
    - "Watt-hours out-put for Railway" (includes Helena Electric Railway Company), 1894-1898 (Box-folder 92 / 2)
- Helena Power Transmission Company
  - Historical Material
    - Historical information file, undated (Box-folder 92 / 3)
  - Interoffice Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous, 1907-1908 (Box-folder 92 / 4)
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - Westinghouse Electric and Manufacturing Company [file continued from Missouri River Power Company subgroup], 1905-1906 (Box-folder 92 / 5-8)
    - Westinghouse Machine Company [continued from Missouri River Power Company subgroup], 1905-1909 (Box-folder 92 / 9-13)
  - General Correspondence
    - Missouri River Power Company (S.T. Hauser, re acquisition), 1905 (Box-folder 92 / 14)
  - Court Papers
    - Helena Power Transmission Company vs. Augustus N. Spratt, et al. (re condemnation of land for dam site at Canyon Ferry), 1910 (Box-folder 93 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - Financial statements, 1908-1909 (Box-folder 93 / 2-3)
    - General ledger, 1905-1906 (Volume 201)
    - General ledger, 1907-1909 (Box-folder 93 / 4)
    - General ledger (includes detailed coal account; damages due to bursting of Hauser Dam; inventories) [Oversize Box], 1908 (Oversizebox 9)
    - Journal (includes detailed entries), 1908 (Volume 202)
    - Journal, 1907-1909 (Box-folder 93 / 5)
    - Voucher registers, 1905-1909 (Volume 203- 205)